

# Kruthi Kunjalu

**DevOps and Cloud Automation Engineer** 

☐: 9100974487 ☐: <u>kkruthi77@gmail.com</u>



### **Professional Summary**

Accomplished Cloud Automation Engineer with an experience of over 5 years in Azure Infrastructure management and automation, Terraform, Configuration Management (Chef), container management (Kubernetes) and Process Automation. An enthusiastic learner, a cloud and DevOps evangelist adept at working in Agile development environments to collaborate and consistently help deliver corporate goals.

# **Accomplishments**

- Delivered optimized cloud services comprising of more than 10,000 resources in Azure environment.
- Handled the infrastructure on AWS for the applications through Terraform.
- Drove cloud cost optimization by delivering savings of \$2400 in Azure cloud management.
- Delivered automation driven savings in Azure through ARM templates (IaC) and PowerShell scripts.
- Implemented efficient configuration management through Chef for RedHat and Windows machines.
- Identified operational inefficiencies and created automated workflows to save manual hours.

#### **Technical Skills**

Cloud: Azure (laaS and PaaS) and AWS(laaS)DevOps: Chef, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform

• Scripting Languages: PowerShell, Python

• Version Control: Git

#### **Certifications**

Microsoft Azure: Implementing Microsoft Azure Infrastructure Solutions.

AWS: Certified Solutions Architect Associate

#### **Experience**

# **DevOps Engineer**

Yara International, Bengaluru

April 2020-Current

- Worked on deploying and managing applications on Kubernetes.
- Set up infrastructure for the applications on AWS using terraform and built CICD pipelines on CircleCI app.
- Managed and monitored the cloud spend by setting up Cloudability for the existing AWS and Kubernetes resources.

#### **Infrastructure Automation Engineer**

Micron Technology, Hyderabad

May 2019-Mar 2020

- Collaborate globally to work on Robotic Process Automation (RPA), DevOps and Infrastructure Automation to enhance the business productivity.
- Lead and developed Azure template-based provisioning to clone the environment within minutes and address the problem of Malicious Data Destruction (MDD). This solution deploys new resources such as VMs using ARM templates, Azure REST APIs and Node.js as the template engine.

#### **Cloud Automation Engineer**

CA Technologies, Hyderabad

Aug 2017-Mar 2019

- Architected the provisioning and maintenance of Azure subscriptions and essential laaS and PaaS services like VNets, Security Groups, VMs, Express Routes, AKS, SQL DB, Web Apps, Service Principals, ARM templates, custom IAM roles, and Azure Security Center.
- Some of the automation use cases implemented in PowerShell:
  - A Backup solution for Azure production VMs.
  - Creation of infrastructure components like VNets and custom roles via ARM Templates.
  - Identification and deletion of orphan VHDs in the Azure subscriptions.
  - Auto shutdown of VMs in the development environment on weekends.
- Automated the end-to-end deployment of customized servers in AWS and Azure through Chef, built startup script in ruby to trigger Chef roles. Some of the use cases of cookbooks would be to install Unix packages, custom software, add the servers to domain, create groups and users etc.
- Addressed the security risks reported by EvidentIO in AWS accounts and brought down the risks by 65%.

#### **Associate Infrastructure Automation Engineer**

CA Technologies, Hyderabad

June 2015 -July 2017

- Developed Chef cookbooks to clean up disk space in Windows and Linux machines.
- Built custom images for Linux and Windows machines in Azure and AWS.
- Automated the end-to-end process of providing users the access to a file share and reduced the manual effort by 70%. Orchestrated the process using Python, JavaScript, and PAM (Process Automation Manager)
- Created an Alexa-Skill to raise tickets for servers whose risk index is greater than 'x'
- Contributed to building automated solutions for cross-functional teams like Service Desk and DBA teams.

# **Awards and Recognition**

- Won 'Start-a-thon', an organization-wide competition to encourage intrapreneurship skills.
- Received several "Above and Beyond" recognition for going beyond what is expected and accoladed for my strong grit and tenacity at work.

# **Voluntary Responsibilities and Interests**

- Represented CA Technologies at GHCI 2016, Bangalore. Conducted Labs on Demand (Live Demo sessions) on UIM integration with Alexa single-handedly.
- Attended the GHCI conferences in 2017 and submitted a presentation for GHCI 2018.
- Organized a booth at the Modern Software Factory (MSF) fair at CA Technologies.
- Conducted Azure training for teams across the organization.
- Volunteered in organizing the Employee Appreciation Week. Actively participated in cultural programs like flash mobs.

## **Education**

B.Tech in CSE (2011-2015), Geethanjali College of Engineering and Technology, Hyderabad GPA:83